This Cherry stands for Yingying.
這櫻桃 就是嬰嬰
It is the advisor of the Apple.
蘋果的謀士
It seems harmless.
看起來人畜無害
But actually, it keeps its own counsel.
實際上是深藏不露
In childhood, Cherry was saved by Apple.
櫻桃小時候被蘋果救過
So it fell head over heels for Apple
所以對蘋果痴心一片
and it's very loyal to Apple.
非常地忠犬
Apple have succeeded in many doings,
蘋果好多做成的事情
which is actually attributed to Cherry's counsel.
其實都少不了櫻桃的出謀劃策
Besides, Apple defeated Banana.
還有打敗香蕉
Well, the Third Princess,
不是 三公主
the story is becoming more and more complex.
這故事真是越編越複雜了
We haven't sorted out the triangular relationship
橙子 蘋果 香蕉的三角關係
between Orange, Apple and Banana yet.
都還沒捋清呢
Why did you bring in another character?
你怎麼又加了一個進來呀
It is not complicated.
不復雜
I brought in Cherry
這櫻桃進來
to help me sort out the relations between characters.
就是幫我理清人物關係的
It has been written into the original script.
這在原劇本里面
Cherry saw that Apple had a thing for Banana.
這櫻桃看出來了蘋果喜歡香蕉
Thus, on Weimeng Mountain, Apple tried all means
所以 才在威猛山上使盡手段
like the typical trapping and drugging.
什麼挖坑 下藥的名場面
It put all those means into practice one by one.
輪番上演
Finally, Banana fell into the trap
最終 香蕉也上了套
and started fancying Apple.
喜歡上了蘋果
This time, as long as
只要這回
Cherry could play its role on Weimeng Mountain
櫻桃也能在威猛山
as specified in the original plots,
發揮原劇情裡面的作用
Han Shuo and Chu...
那韓爍跟楚
Then, Banana and Apple
那 那香蕉跟蘋果
will come to fruition in love.
這事也就是成了
Then I will be able to
那我就可以
rest and wait for the finale.
坐等大結局了
Now the plots have changed too much.
這個現在劇情改變得太多了
I am very curious.
我倒是好奇呀
How should Cherry act
這個櫻桃要如何做
to clean up the mess
才能把之前橙子捅的窟窿
made by Orange in the past.
都給補上
Qianqian.
芊芊
Be careful.
小心
Su Ziying, how could you?
蘇子嬰 你
I implore you not to misunderstand, Young Master Han.
求韓少君不要誤會
I'm just worried that the strong wind
小人只是怕風大
might cause Her Highness to catch a cold.
三公主感染風寒
If I did anything improper,
如果哪裡做得不對
please forgive me.
還請少君包涵
What are you doing?
你這是做什麼
Why did you make Yingying kneel down?
你幹嗎讓嬰嬰跪著呀
I didn't make him do that.
不是我讓他跪的
Your Highness,
回三公主
I have offended Young Master Han.
小人觸怒了韓少君
So he punished me lightly.
韓少君才對小人略施小懲
Sorry to have disturbed Your Highness.
驚擾三公主了
When did I punish you?
我什麼時候罰你了
Young Master Han,
韓少君
if you are annoyed with me,
您若對小人有不滿
I am willing to be beaten and punished.
小人認打認罰
However,
但是
you mustn't misunderstand
您千萬不要誤解我家公子
my Young Master's kindness to Her Highness.
對三公主的好意
Did I say a word about Pei Heng?
我哪個字提到裴恆了
Han Shuo,
韓爍
it is true that Pei Heng sent Yingying here
裴恆送嬰嬰過來
only to take care of me.
真的只是照顧我的
Moreover,
再說了
Yingying is well-behaved and obedient.
嬰嬰又乖又聽話的
Don't always think others are ill-intentioned.
你不要總是把人想得這麼壞
OK?
好不好
Yingying, get into the carriage.
嬰嬰 你上車吧
I want to have a talk with you.
我有話跟你說
Young Master,
少君
you have been thumping your chest these days.
您近日頻頻捶胸
Has your heart disease relapsed?
是不是心疾又犯了
It is not the heart disease.
不是心疾
I am suffering from the chest tightness.
是堵得慌
Han Shuo,
韓爍
go consult with Chuchu
你去找二姐商量商量
about our itinerary today.
我們今天的行程吧
As for you two,
你們兩個
one is both brainy and brawny
一個智勇雙全
and the other is good at governing troops.
一個治軍有道的
With you two here,
有你們在
I feel a lot more at ease.
我就放心多了
You two must have a good discussion
就是你們倆個得好好地商量
in a detailed fashion.
仔仔細細地商量
Have you got it?
明白嗎
Just go.
去去去
Your Highness.
二郡主
Young Master Han.
韓少君
Weimeng Mt. features complex terrain and can be easily guarded.
威猛山地勢複雜 易守難攻
Do you have any sound strategies
不知少君有何良策
to ensure an immediate victory.
能馬到成功
Meng Guo is pretentious.
孟過狂妄
Learning that we are coming suppress his forces,
得知有人來圍剿
he won't hole up in the mountain.
不會龜縮在山中
Look! We shall get stationed here.
看 咱們駐紮在此處
Then we will find a chance to lure him out
找個機會引蛇出洞
to capture him.
將他擒獲
But we still need bait.
但還缺個誘餌
In my view, Su Ziying is a good choice.
我看蘇子嬰就挺不錯的
Su Ziying?
蘇子嬰
Just kidding.
說笑的
Su Ziying is just a humble wretch
蘇子嬰不過是個身份低微
who is adept in artful speech.
巧言令色的小人
What capability and virtue does he have
何德何能
to lure Meng Guo down the mountain?
能讓孟過下山一趟
As the Young Master of Xuanhu City,
韓某身為玄虎少君
I will put the word out
到時候要把消息放出去
to get him to come at me by then.
讓他來擒我
Your Highness,
郡主
here is the sesame paste, ginseng tea,
這是今日的芝麻糊 人蔘茶
the pearl barley dew, and the bird's nest.
薏仁水和燕窩
They are all premium tonics.
都是滋補佳品
In such beautiful days,
大好的時光
only a worthless person like me
只有我這種廢人
stays at home to kill time.
留在家裡虛度光陰
Life is short.
人生苦短
When can I be freed from all this?
也不知道我能否早日解脫
Your Highness,
郡主
don't be self-despising.
您就是再瞧不上自己
The Third Princess is inferior to you.
不還有三公主墊底嗎
Even if she has been made Crown Princess,
就算當了少城主
she continues idling away day in, day out.
她也是整日遊手好閒
Minister Pei just handled the official documents for her.
連公文都是裴司學幫忙處理的
Your Highness, Mr. Su is present.
郡主 蘇公子來了
Greetings to you, Your Highness.
小人 見過大郡主
Why are you here?
你怎麼來了
Where is Qianqian?
芊芊呢
the Crown Princess has been sent to Weimeng Mountain to suppress bandits.
少城主被城主派去威猛山剿匪
She has left at around 8 a.m.
辰時已經出發了
She ordered me
她派人吩咐小的
to accompany you through the rehabilitation every day.
要我每日來陪著您做復健
Qianqian has gone to suppress the bandits?
芊芊去剿匪了
Zi Nian,
梓年
didn't you say Qianqian
你不是說三公主
was idling away all the time?
她整日遊手好閒嗎
I will skip the rehabilitation.
不練了
Zi Nian.
梓年
Your Highness.
大郡主
Why are you still here?
你怎麼還沒走
Why is Your Highness so childish?
大郡主怎麼還像小孩子一樣
You wrote your will in the form of diary.
把遺書當日記寫
You!
你
How dare you!
放肆
You mustn't read them.
你不許看
Your Highness,
大郡主
you really
您是當真
don't want me to read them?
不想讓蘇沐看嗎
Read them if you insist.
要看 就看吧
This is the first letter.
這第一封
New Year's Eve in the 9th year during Empress Fengde's reign
鳳德九年 除夕
Her Majesty and my third sister played on ice.
母后與三妹冰嬉
I was itching for joining them.
心癢難耐
Your Highness wanted to go skating.
大郡主想要滑冰
This is the second one.
這第二封
Your Highness.
郡主
The Dragon Boat Festival in the 11th year during Empress Fengde's reign
鳳德十一年 端午
Third sister rode a horse in the street and fell off it.
三妹縱馬長街 不慎摔落
I envied her so much.
羨慕
Your Highness,
大郡主
so you wanted to ride a horse.
原來你想騎馬
I, your servant can fulfill your wish.
這小人 可以辦到
The next one.
這接下來一封
The third diary.
第三封
Fengde...
鳳德
The year is not important.
這其實年份都不重要了
As Your Highness grew up,
這無非都是郡主越來越大
you wanted to try more and more things.
想要的 就越來越多
Fly a kite.
放風箏
Your Highness,
大郡主
you have never flown a kite?
你莫非還沒放過風箏
You also wanted to go to the Music and Dance Academy.
還想去教坊司
The Music and Dance Academy
這教坊司
is not a good place.
可不是一個好地方
But, they all have visited it.
可 可她們都去過
Your Highness need not go there.
大郡主不必去教坊司
Back then, the service of all musicians
想當年 眾樂人百般討好
couldn't outdo my hearty smile.
這也不及蘇某的傾心一笑啊
Let me read this last one.
讓我看一下這最後一封
Your Highness
這大郡主把心裡話
has put down all your inner thoughts in the letters.
都寫進信裡了
Now they are dropped onto the ground.
這扔在地上
What a pity!
難道不可惜嗎
I just put down some random thoughts.
我亂寫的
As long as Your Highness agrees to practice
只要大郡主答應小人
referring to the brochure given by the Crown Princess,
按照少城主的圖冊練習
I will try my best
那小人必定想盡辦法
to enable you to ride a horse, go skating and fly a kite.
帶你騎馬 滑冰 放風箏
Besides,
還有啊
you need not go to the Music and Dance Academy.
這教坊司 想必就不用去了
No matter what the musicians there can do,
教坊司樂人會的
I can do the same, too.
小人都會
I didn't want to go there.
誰想去了
I just wrote the words randomly.
我亂寫的
You are holding one in your hands.
這還有您手裡這封
No matter what wish
無論裡邊
you have put down in the letter,
是什麼願望
I will help you fulfill your wish.
小人一定會幫您實現
Really?
當真
Your Highness,
大郡主
are you thinking that I come from the Music and Dance Academy,
您是嫌棄小人出身教坊司
so I am used to cheating women
慣會欺騙女人
and breaking my words?
說的話不當數
Of course not.
當然不是
You are not like others.
你跟別人不一樣
Forget it.
算了
You don't know
你根本就不知道
what I wrote in this letter at all.
這封信箋裡寫了什麼
I won't take your words seriously.
我只當你胡說的
Then, for the next, we shall...
那 接下來我們
Let's practice.
練吧
OK.
好
Mr. Su,
蘇公子
from now on,
從今往後
you will be our Risheng Mansion's honored guest.
您就是日晟府的貴客
It is the Crown Princess's duty to suppress the bandits.
這剿匪明明是少城主的差事
How come in the end,
怎麼到頭來
it has become your business?
卻是您在前前後後張羅
She is the Crown Princess.
她是少城主
Though you're working for her,
您給她打下手
by then, she will take all the credit.
到時候肯定有什麼功勞都是她的
But if things go wrong, you will be held accountable.
出了差錯卻是您的
It is unfair.
憑什麼
Never mind.
算了
It is no use saying these words now.
到現在了還說這些有什麼用
Don't you think the air in this carriage
你們有沒有覺得這個車裡有點
is oxygen-deficient?
缺氧
I think it is too crowded
我覺得 三個人坐
for three people.
還是有點太擁擠了
Let one of us get out.
咱 下去一個吧
I am a humble servant.
小人身份卑微
I will get out.
小人下去
Nonetheless,
只是
it has been a long travel.
這一路舟車勞頓
Her Highness must have been tired.
三公主乘車難免疲乏
I have mastered the massage.
小人有一套按摩推拿的手法
You can do that?
你還會這個
A small piece of cake.
雕蟲小技
Could you please get out to ride the horse?
要不你下去騎會兒馬吧
I want the massage.
我按摩一會兒
I can do it, too.
我也會
I will give you the massage.
我幫你按
In my memory, you can't.
我記得你不會啊
I can.
我可以會
What are you doing?
你幹嗎
Let him massage me first.
他先幫我按按
Then I will learn it.
我不就會了
Han Shuo, you can't bully Yingying.
韓爍 你能不能不要欺負嬰嬰啊
Who bullied him?
誰欺負他了
He likes kneeling down.
他這動不動就跪的毛病
Maybe Pei Heng taught him to do so.
保不齊就是裴恆教他的
For no reason,
你這好端端地
why did you mention Pei Heng again?
又提裴恆做什麼
Pei Heng! Pei Heng! Pei Heng!
裴恆 裴恆 裴恆
Your Highness,
三公主
don't bicker with
你不要因為小人
Young Master Han for my sake.
與韓少君爭吵呀
We didn't quarrel, right?
咱們沒有吵架 是吧
No, we didn't.
對 沒吵
We didn't.
沒吵
You want a massage, right?
按摩是吧
I will massage you.
我也給你按
Why does one man pick on another man?
男人何苦為難男人呢
It feels good!
舒服
This letter
這封
was written when the Third Princess got married.
是三公主大婚的時候寫下的
If my memory doesn't lie to me,
小人沒記錯的話
Your Highness made a wish that
郡主許的願望
you could find someone to love.
是願得一心人
Su Mu didn't know his inferiority
不知天高地厚的蘇沐
and dared to promise you this.
他連這個都敢答應
Geez! Your Highness!
天哪 郡主
Have you fallen for him?
您不會是看上
He is the number one of the Music and Dance Academy.
他可是教坊司的頭牌
He is just a musician.
一個樂人
He doesn't look down upon me.
他不嫌棄我
Why should I make light of him?
我又有什麼資格看輕他
As long as the man is good to Your Highness
只要能對郡主好
and makes Your Highness happy,
討郡主喜歡
he will be the right one.
就是對的人
God, please bless Her Highness with early recovery
求老天爺保佑我們家郡主
and may her wishes come true.
早日康復 心想事成
Take care.
慢一點
Our inn
這客棧呀
used to enjoy business boom.
以前也是生意興隆
Since the bandits on the Weimeng Mountain
自從這威猛山的山匪
began to harass the passing trade caravans,
老是下山騷擾商隊
well,
這不
our business has been stagnant.
小店的生意是越來越不好做了
Our inn is old and in bad repair.
小店年久失修
We can only provide a limited number of rooms.
能住的房間也有限
I don't know what arrangements I should make.
不知 該如何安排呀
Prepare three high-quality rooms
給少君和兩位郡主
for my master and the two princesses.
準備三間上房
Three rooms?
三間
Won't Young Master and the Crown Princess share one room?
少君跟少城主不同屋嗎
Right. Then the Crown Princess and I will...
對 那就安排我跟少城主
You asked too much.
囉唆
My master made such arrangements
我們少君這麼安排
for his own purpose.
自有他的用意
I got it.
明白 明白
I will do it right away.
馬上 馬上
Bai Ji,
白芨
what is my purpose on earth?
我究竟有什麼用意呀
It hurts a lot.
疼疼疼
Young Master,
少君
you have taken the drastic measure.
釜底已經抽過薪了
Though the Crown Princess is important,
少城主固然重要
what is on your mind now
但是您現在心裡惦記的
should be the forces of Weimeng Mountain.
是威猛山的人馬
You want to take this chance to subdue Meng Guo
您想趁此機會收服孟過
to make him work for you
化為己用
and make him escort the trade caravans of our Xuanhu City.
讓其護送玄虎商隊的往來
It is a serious matter.
此等大事
I guess you don't want the Crown Princess to know it.
我猜 您不想讓少城主察覺吧
So you must take separate rooms.
自然要分房而睡
Young Master, is my analysis right?
少君 我分析得對嗎
Yes.
對啊
I have such a plan indeed.
我確實有此計劃
Young Master, you are circumspect and far-sighted.
少君深謀遠慮
Young Master, you are wise.
少君英明
Looking back smilingly,
巧笑回首
a lady that is so slim and graceful.
翩若驚鴻影
Her eyes are slightly-parted
明眸微啟
looking like bows in the moonlight.
宛如月下弓
In the deep forest of the back mountain,
後山林深處
I will wait for your arrival, my lady.
靜候佳人
Holding a sword with a heroic bearing,
仗劍英姿
a man looks so imposing.
威風掃八面
Spurring a horse with the raised whip,
策馬揚鞭
a man seems so domineering.
霸氣蕩九州
In the deep forest of the back mountain,
後山林深處
I will wait for your arrival, dear sir.
靜候郎君
You two,
你們倆啊
hand over
分別把這封信
one letter to Chuchu
一封 交給楚楚
and the other to Young Master Han.
一封 交給韓少君
Remember
記住
not to let others know
千萬不能讓別人知道
I wrote them.
這是我寫的
Got it.
明白
Let the plots
那就讓劇情
develop more quickly and surprisingly.
來得更猛烈一些吧
Declaring love on Weimeng Mountain.
情定威猛山
A lady that is so slim and graceful.
翩若驚鴻
He asked me to meet him on the back mountain.
他約我在後山相見
Why did the Second Princess ask you to the back mountain?
二郡主為何約您在後山相見
Holding a sword with a heroic bearing.
仗劍英姿
Could it be possible that
難道
she wants us to...
她是想與我
Laugh!
笑
Laugh out aloud!
大聲笑
This is how an idol drama should be.
這才是偶像劇的正確打開方式嘛
Such a feast to eyes.
太養眼了
Your Highness.
二郡主
Young Master Han, why did you
少君約我此次前來
ask me to meet you here?
是為了
Your Highness, please strike.
二郡主 出招吧
Strike?
出招
Since you mentioned holding a sword,
既然提到仗劍英姿
I guess our battle in the Music and Dance Academy,
想必是教坊司一戰
has failed to satisfy you.
二郡主未能盡興
Taking this chance,
正好藉此機會
let's battle it out again.
我們再次切磋
We are facing the fight with the bandits.
剿匪一役當前
It suits the occasion.
倒也應景
Battle it out?
比試
Isn't this a date?
不是 這 這不是約會嗎
The Music and Dance Academy... Battle...
教坊司 切磋
So I misunderstood it.
原來是我理解錯了
You didn't.
不是你理解錯
Han Shuo did.
是韓爍他理解錯 他
Your Highness, please strike.
二郡主 出招
It doesn't matter.
無妨 無妨 無妨
The hero and heroine
這個男女主角
may fall for each other while crossing swords.
練劍也能擦出火花
In the martial art competition,
比武嘛
they will exchange blows
它 你來我往
and can't avoid physical contact.
至少得有點身體接觸
Thus, they may develop feelings for each other.
隨之互生情愫
As I said.
我就說嘛
Go on!
再來
This is not good.
完了
The idol drama is turning into the Kung Fu drama.
這是偶像劇要變成武俠劇了
You should go easy on her.
你讓著她呀
How can you be so serious
跟女孩子比武你
when battling with a girl?
怎麼那麼狠呢
You won't be popular with girls.
注孤生
What should I do? What should I do?
怎麼辦 怎麼辦
I got distracted.
是小人一時失察
Please punish me, Your Highness.
請三公主責罰
Who is there? Show yourself.
什麼人 出來
Me.
我
It is me.
我 我
Qianqian.
芊芊
You...
你
I
我
was passing by.
途經此處
By chance,
偶然
by accident and without intention,
不小心 無意間
I saw you and Chuchu battling here.
就 就看見你跟二姐在這兒切磋
So I hid myself quietly
然後我就悄咪咪
not to disturb you.
不讓你們發現地躲起來
Then I watched you for a while.
然後看了一會兒
Master Han, you fought so valiantly.
少君打得可真是英勇瀟灑
Chuchu,
二姐
you have fought hard.
辛苦了
In this battle, you two
你們倆打的這一番
can be said to
就特別地
be a good match,
棋逢對手
to be equal in strength,
不分上下
to be on a par
難分伯仲
and to be similarly skilled in martial arts.
勢均力敵
Bravo!
好
You are a heaven-made match.
天作之合
A heaven-made match. A perfect match.
天作之合 郎才女貌 對
I am not on a par with her.
我哪跟她棋逢對手
I won just now.
我剛才明明贏了
So Young Master Han, you asked me to meet you here
原來少君約我在此處見面
for the purpose of showing me up.
就是為了讓人看我笑話的
No, it is not like that, Chuchu.
不是的 二姐
Don't you see... second sister...
沒看著 二 二
Did I fight bravely just now?
我剛才打得虎不虎啊
Yes.
虎
Then I will feel assured.
那便好
Didn't you see I was just being polite?
聽不出來我在給你臺階下
Chuchu is a girl of noble birth.
楚楚天之驕女
But you humiliated her so much.
被你搞得這麼狼狽
She must be very sad now.
回去多難受啊
Since we were in a battle,
既然是切磋
if I had gone easy on her,
那如果我退讓的話
that would have been disrespect to her.
那就是對二郡主的不尊重
So, do you mean that
那你的意思是
if I hadn't stopped you,
我要是不出來攔著
you would have beaten her up.
你還要往死裡打了
Since it was a friendly battle,
既然是切磋
I wouldn't hurt her.
那當然是點到為止
Her life would not be in danger.
不會出人命的
Besides, she is your sister. I...
況且她是你姐姐 我
I got it.
我明白了
You are blaming me for applying too much strength.
你是在怪我下手太重
It is my fault.
怪我
I shouldn't have given you the one-track-minded persona.
怪我給了你這個一根筋的人設
A person like you
你這種人啊
is basically not fit for the idol drama.
基本上是告別偶像劇
Well, what am I not fit for?
不是 告別什麼
Your Highness,
少城主
wait for me!
等等我
Master Han, in our Huayuan City,
少君 我們花垣城有句話
there is a saying, a man's best dowry
冰清玉潔 守身自愛
is his chastity, purity and self-respect.
是男人最好的嫁妝
Please act prudently in the coming days,
往後行事還請謹慎些
observe the men's ethics,
恪守夫德
and try not to rile the Third Princess.
少惹三公主生氣吧
I...
我
Young Master, what did Su Ziying mean?
少君 蘇子嬰他什麼意思
He might mean that...
可能是說
Qianqian thought I met the Second Princess for a date.
芊芊誤會我與二郡主私會
It seems that it is a wise move for me
看來我帶她來剿匪
to have brought her to suppress the bandits.
果然是明智之舉呀
She
她竟
got jealous of me.
為我心生醋意
Yingying, you have seen it.
嬰嬰 你也看到了
What do you think of
你覺得韓少君跟二郡主的關係
the relation between Han Shuo and my second sister?
怎麼樣
I think that
小人覺得
Xuanhu City and Huayuan City have different folk customs.
玄虎城與花垣城民俗不同
Are Your Highness also suspecting that
難道 三公主也懷疑少君
Master Han is harboring evil designs?
有不軌之心
He isn't harboring any ill intent.
不軌倒沒有
Because from the very beginning,
因為他從一開始
he has been acting oddly.
就沒有進入過正軌
Normally,
這按理說
he should be closer to Chuchu.
他應該跟楚楚更近一點的
I don't understand.
小人不懂
Help me figure out a way
你幫我想個辦法
to push Han Shuo to Chuchu's side.
讓韓少君去楚楚那邊
Your Highness, I have been taught by Mr. Pei
三公主 小人受裴公子教誨
to be kind to people and behave properly.
與人為善 安守本分
I dare not do improper things.
不敢造次
Don't pretend in front of me.
你還跟我在這兒裝
Because you are resourceful,
當初就是因為你點子多
I brought you here to suppress the bandits.
我才願意帶你來剿匪的
You can take it that
你就想著說是
I
就當作是我
got tired of Han Shuo
厭煩了韓爍
and asked you to figure out a solution for me
讓你幫我想個法子
to scuttle our marriage.
攪黃我與他的婚事
Such is the thing.
這樣
Since Your Highness gave me the order,
既然是三公主的吩咐
I would go through fire and water to do it.
小人赴湯蹈火 在所不辭
But I am slow-witted.
只是 小人愚笨
How should I do it?
該如何行事
Please give me instructions, Your Highness.
還請三公主示下
When suppressing bandits, perils are unavoidable.
剿匪之際 多有險境
I think the love between two people
我覺得兩個人的感情
will be born out of mutual trust
應該是從相互信賴
and interdependence.
依靠開始的
They...
他們
Rest assured, Your Highness.
三公主放心
I got it. I will do as you said.
小人懂了 小人遵命
He got it.
這就懂了
But I haven't got it quite well.
我還不太懂呢
Something is happening.
有情況
Report!
報
Your Highness,
啟稟二郡主
while Young Master Han was leading the troops on patrol,
韓少君帶兵巡防
they were ambushed by the bandits.
中了山匪埋伏
Zi Zhu,
梓竹
you lead men to aid Young Master Han.
你帶人先去接應韓少君
I will go check the situation and come right away.
我去查看情況 立馬就來
Be careful, Your Highness.
郡主小心
Young Master, haven't you been ambushed?
少君 您不是中了埋伏
What ambush?
什麼埋伏
Where is the Second Princess?
二郡主人呢
Report came that
有人來報
you have been ambushed by the bandits.
說少君您巡防中了山匪埋伏
So the Second Princess sent me to aid you.
二郡主特派我先來接應您
Where is the messenger?
來通報的人呢
I am afraid Meng Guo is trying to lure us away.
怕是孟過的調虎離山之計
The Second Princess is in danger now.
二郡主有危險
Zi Zhu, lead the way.
梓竹 帶路
Yes, sir!
是
If mother comes to know that
要是讓母親知道
in the course of suppressing bandits,
我在剿匪路上
I fall into the trap accidentally
因為意外墜下陷阱
and fail to complete the mission,
沒有完成任務
she will surely scold me.
母親定會訓斥我
Master Han,
少君
could the mountain bandits have arrived
莫不是山匪來襲
and she's been taken by Meng Guo?
被孟過他們抓走了吧
Qianqian and her second sister are close.
芊芊和二郡主姐妹情深
She can't bear to see her sister in danger.
定不願看她置身險境
Let's find her first.
我們先將人找到
Master Han, why are you here?
少君 怎麼是你
I came to save you.
我來救你
Your leg has got hurt.
郡主腿受傷了
Let me help you handle it.
我幫你處理一下
Your Highness is brave and strong.
二郡主性情堅毅
If Qianqian was in your position,
如果此時是芊芊
she would cry loudly.
早就大呼小叫了
You lied to me, Young Master Han.
少君哄我
Qianqian fears no pain.
三妹從不怕疼
Come on.
來
Sorry to trouble you, Young Master Han.
勞煩少君了
Don't mention it.
無妨 不足掛齒
Your foot just got better.
你腳傷剛好
I will carry you up on my back.
我揹你上去
Thank you, Young Master Han.
多謝少君
Zi Rui,
梓銳兄
I saw some food stock in the kitchen.
我在客棧廚房看到一些存糧
So I wanted to cook congee for the Third Princess tomorrow morning.
想著明早煮粥給三公主喝
But I am not good at cooking.
只是 我廚藝不精
I can't even cook the congee.
連碗粥都不會
OK. I will work on it.
行 我去看看
The Third Princess, I got everything done.
三公主 都安排好了
At this time, Young Master Han and the Second Princess
此時韓少君
should be having a good time together.
應該與二郡主花前月下了
It happened so fast.
動作這麼快的嗎
Come on.
來
In childhood, I took Qianqian for pack hunting.
小時候帶著芊芊圍獵
She liked this kind of wild fruit best.
她最喜歡吃這種野果
Does she still like it?
她現在還喜歡吃嗎
Who knows?
誰知道呢
Her feelings for things never last long.
她對什麼都不太長情
Why did you pack it?
你把它收起來做什麼
I will bring it back to Qianqian.
帶回去給芊芊吃
She is not used to the cold food for the marching troops.
她吃不慣行軍的冷食餐飯
If I had known Young Master Han is so brave and handsome
早知少君這樣神勇俊朗
as well as is so devoted to love,
又痴情專一
I shouldn't have let Qianqian have you.
當初就不該把你讓給芊芊
Why did you say so, Your Highness?
二郡主何出此言
Back then, when you entered our city,
當日你進城
mother intended to marry me to you.
母親本有意安排我們成婚
But Qianqian was taking you by force in the street,
只是三妹當街搶親
which resulted in your marriage with her by chance.
才意外促成了你們的姻緣
This is the trick fate played on us.
還真是命運弄人哪
If I were given another chance,
如果再給我一次機會
I hope I would be riding a horse in the street
我真希望當日策馬長街的人是我
and be taking you from the street.
當街搶親的人也是我
If time could go back,
如果時光重來
what would be your choice, Young Master Han?
少君又會如何選擇
Though I came to know Qianqian by accident,
我與芊芊相識雖然是意外
after a series of happenings,
但經過幾番波折
I have developed deep feelings for her.
韓某對芊芊已經是情根深種
If there were a second chance,
若還有第二次機會
I would still choose Qianqian, who is pure-hearted,
韓某依然會選擇那個心思單純
upright and kind.
耿直善良的三公主
With your talent, Your Highness,
憑藉二郡主的一身才華
you will definitely make great achievements in the future.
日後定當有所作為
Your Highness, I wish that
韓某祝願二郡主
you could enjoy endless blessings.
曼福不盡
Just as I expected.
果然如此
People in the whole Huayuan City
整個花垣城的人
know you love Qianqian.
都知道你喜歡陳芊芊
But she doesn't know herself.
但她卻總是不懂的樣子
Qianqian
芊芊她
is pure-hearted.
心思單純
There is a place for me in her heart.
她心裡是有我的
On the marching journey, we can't make a fire.
行軍途中不便生火
Sorry to make you suffer.
辛苦二郡主了
Thank you, Young Master Han.
謝少君
Though I am a noble princess,
我雖貴為郡主
people seldom treat me so nicely.
但少有人如此待我
You can't be serious, Your Highness.
二郡主說笑了
Qianqian
芊芊自幼
has been loved by all people since childhood.
集萬千寵愛於一身
She is spoiled and willful
驕縱任性
while I am used to currying favor with people.
而我卻從小要學著察言觀色
Mother hasn't been good to me
母親對我
as she has been nice to Qianqian.
並不如待芊芊那樣親厚
Qianqian doesn't take anything to heart,
芊芊什麼事都漫不經心
but she has everything.
卻樣樣佔盡
I tried my best in everything,
我所有事情都拼盡全力
but I got nothing.
卻都是一場空
Young Master Han, tell me,
少君 你說
is this my destiny?
這是不是命
You are just having a hard time temporarily.
二郡主只是一時不如意
Don't mind it too much.
不必放在心上
Things will change for the better
二郡主定會守得雲開
and you will have your moments.
見月明
People in the whole Huayuan City
整個花垣城的人
know you love Qianqian.
都知道你喜歡陳芊芊
But she doesn't know herself.
但她卻總是不懂的樣子
Qianqian is pure-hearted.
芊芊她 心思單純
There is a place for me in her heart.
心裡自然是有我的
Is it true that
芊芊她
Qianqian doesn't know my feelings?
真的不懂我嗎
They didn't come back last night.
這人呢 一宿未歸
Does a date have to take so long?
那約個會需要這麼久嗎
Where have you led them?
你把人給安排到哪兒去了
They fell into a trap.
掉陷阱了
Trap?
陷阱
Who dug it?
這 誰挖
You dug it?
你挖的
Isn't this your idea, Your Highness?
這 這不三公主您的主意嗎
My idea?
我的主意
When suppressing bandits, traps are unavoidable.
剿匪之際 多有陷阱
perils are unavoidable.
剿匪之際 多有險境
Don't you know?
險境你知不知道
You took traps for perils.
這諧音梗是要扣錢的
I made a mistake.
小人會錯意了
But you said that
可您又說
two people' feelings
兩個人的感情
are born out of mutual trust
都是從相互信賴
and interdependence.
依靠開始的
That doesn't mean you can dig a pit
那你也不能給他倆挖個坑
and bury them.
埋起來啊
If Meng Guo passed by
那萬一孟過路經此地
and filled up the pit with earth,
把這個坑順便給填滿了
they would lose their lives.
他們倆不就 沒命了
I have been careless.
是小人的疏忽
Please punish me, Your Highness.
請三公主責罰
How should I?
責罰什麼
Where did you trap them? Go save them!
埋哪兒了 救人
Hurry!
快點
the Crown Princess, the Crown Princess.
少城主 少城主
Look at the food I prepared for you.
你看 我為你準備了什麼
It is congee? Why?
粥啊 怎麼
You made a fire?
你生火了
When I went to cook the congee this morning,
我今天早上去廚房煮粥的時候
the pot had been put above the fire.
這鍋就已經煮上了
You made the fire?
你生的
It has been a tiring journey.
這一路勞頓
Seeing Your Highness could only eat cold food
我看三公主只吃冷食
and had no hot meals,
連口熱的都沒有
I decided to cook a bowl of congee
就想著煮碗粥
to warm your stomach.
給您暖暖身子
While on the march,
行軍途中
in order to keep our traces secret,
為避免暴露行蹤
we are forbidden to make a fire.
不燃炊煙
Hurry to circulate the order.
趕緊通傳下去
Set out immediately!
立即開拔 立即開拔
If Meng Guo came to attack,
這萬一孟過打過來
in the absence of Han Shuo and Chuchu, I...
這韓爍 楚楚不在 我就
Well,
不行
I have to lead some men to save them.
我還得帶一隊人馬去救他們
In case that Meng Guo find them first...
那萬一孟過先去找他們
Report!
報
Your Highness,
啟稟少城主
the mountain bandits are coming at us.
山匪打過來了
They are coming?
打過來了
Run! Run! Run!
跑跑跑 跑
Well. Well.
這這這
Capture Chen Qianqian! Make her my wife!
生擒少城主 霸佔陳芊芊
Hurry! Hurry!
快快快
Be careful!
小心
What should we do?
這怎麼辦
Your Highness, run away quickly!
三公主 你快逃啊
I will cover for you.
小人會掩護您的
Get out of here quickly!
你快走
I am...
我是
No! No! No! I am not.
不不不 我不是
Your Highness, take flight!
三公主 快逃
Your Highness!
三公主
Shut up!
閉嘴吧你
Your Highness! Run! Your Highness!
三公主 你快跑 三公主
Are you all right?
你沒事吧
Go help Chuchu quickly!
快去幫楚楚 快
Are you kidding?
你開什麼玩笑
How can I leave you alone?
我怎麼可能丟下你不管
Don't mind me.
你先不要管我
It is not easy for you to have a chance
你好不容易跟楚楚
to spend a whole night with Chuchu in the trap.
在陷阱裡處了一夜
Hurry to help her.
你趕快去幫她
How do you know we were in the trap?
你怎麼知道我們困在陷阱
Han Shuo, are you all right?
韓爍 你有沒有事啊
-Zi Rui, take Qianqian somewhere to hide. -Does it hurt?
梓銳 你先帶芊芊躲起來
-Yes! -Han Shuo!
是
Hurry!
快去
Does it hurt?
你疼不疼
Han Shuo!
韓爍
Report to Your Highness.
啟稟少城主
Here is Meng Guo, ringleader of the Weimeng Mountain bandits.
此人乃威猛山山匪首領孟過
Weimeng Mountain is located at the junction
威猛山位於花垣玄虎
of Huayuan City and Xuanhu City.
兩城交界之處
Our trade caravans pass it inevitably.
是往來商隊的必經之路
Meng Guo occupies it and robs the passers-by.
孟過佔據此山 攔路搶劫
The passing trade caravans suffer a lot.
過往商隊苦不堪言
Now he is captured.
現已將其擒獲
How should we deal with him?
如何處置
Han Shuo, hurry to put in a good word for him.
韓爍 趕緊求情收下他吧
In the original script,
原劇本里
Meng Guo was a right-hand man of you.
孟過可是你麾下一員猛將
Since he is caught, he should be killed.
既然抓住了 就將他殺了
Mother sent us here
母親派我們此次前來
for nothing else, but this matter.
就是為了解決此事
Why is "kill" said so easily?
怎麼說著就要殺呢
It is frightening.
多嚇人啊
In your opinion, the Crown Princess,
那依少城主
what should we do with him?
該如何處置
I...
我
How about your opinion, Young Master Han?
少君呢
Young Master Han, do you want this man?
少君 打不打算要這個人
Fine. I will keep him alive.
也好 那就留著此人
Keep him...
留在
A real man can be killed, but not humiliated.
大丈夫士可殺不可辱
It is a pity that I was defeated.
可惜我功敗垂成
Otherwise,
要不然
I will take her to my mountain
我就將她押到我山上
and make her my wife.
做壓寨夫人
We can live a happy life.
風流快活
Take my banner here.
把老子橫幅拿來
Where is my banner?
橫幅呢
What banner?
什麼橫幅
I don't know.
不清楚啊
Capture Chen Qianqian!
生擒少城主
Make her my wife!
霸佔陳芊芊
Then he should be beheaded.
那就把他砍了 砍了
Behead?
砍
Well, don't you want him to work for you?
不是 你 你不要了
Think about the forces and mines of Weimeng Mountain.
威猛山的人馬 礦
Don't give up on him.
別不要他呀
He harbors ill intent towards you.
此人對你包藏禍心
If you don't want him, I will.
那你不要 我要
Meng Guo has evil designs and occupies the mountain for brigandage.
孟過居心叵測 佔山為匪
He not only persecutes the people,
迫害百姓不說
but also wants to make you his wife by force.
還想把你押回去當壓寨夫人
You are dreaming.
你簡直痴心妄想
I was inspired.
我有一個靈感
Meng Guo is a good name.
孟過這個名字好
I suddenly recalled an allusion.
我突然想起來一個典故
Have you ever heard...
你們有聽說過
Who?
誰呀
Have, have you heard of
你們 你們有聽說過那個
Zhuge Kongming?
諸葛孔明嗎
Who is it?
此為何人
A military counselor.
一個軍師
Shall I invite him here?
要把他請來嗎
No need. I am capable enough.
不用了 有我在就好
Free him.
把 把他放了吧
Why?
為啥
Why are you still in the mood to ask about the reason?
我要放你 你還問我為啥
Do you want to be beheaded?
等著被砍哪
Kill me if you want to.
要殺便殺
Today I just brought a small troop
我今日就是帶了一小隊人馬
to gather military intelligence.
前來刺探軍情
I find that your military camps a-a-re
看你軍營空空空
neglectful of necessary precautions.
空虛
Thus, I launched a surprise attack.
我才來偷襲
It is really a pity.
可惜
You can behead me.
你砍了我也行
My men on Weimeng Mountain will revenge me.
我威猛山兄弟定會報仇
Did, did you hear?
你 你們聽到了嗎
If we kill Meng Guo today,
今日如果把孟過給殺了
the bandits will lose their leader.
那威猛山無首
It will be a serious problem in the future.
日後必有大患
It will be harder for us to deal with them.
更加難治理
Based on the strength of Young Master Han and Chuchu,
想必 以韓少君跟二姐的實力
it must be easy to catch the bandits.
擒拿威猛山山匪再簡單不過了
However, what matters now is
但現在重要的是
we have to make them stop
我們要讓他們改掉這種
seizing others' possessions.
侵犯他人私人財產的行為
We should persuade them to work for us.
說服他們 為我所用
Free him.
放了吧
Nothing matters as long as Qianqian is fine.
芊芊沒事就行了
Hurry!
快點
I know how to walk.
我自己會走
Get out of my way.
讓開
Are you sure it will work, Qianqian?
三妹此舉 可有把握
Yes.
有
Meng Guo is meant to be caught seven times.
七擒孟過嘛
Then he will be freed seven times.
七抓七放
After that, he will submit willingly.
必定心悅誠服
Sorry.
對不起啊
I got you distracted.
讓你分心了
I am to blame for this.
這件事怪我
I haven't come back earlier.
沒能早點趕回來
Just now, you wanted to
你剛剛
block the sword attack for me.
想替我擋刀
I saw it clearly.
我全看在眼裡
It doesn't matter.
沒事
From now on, in no case
以後無論如何
can you do this again.
都不許再這樣
There is something else
還有些事
to be clarified.
要弄個清楚明白
Last night, Young Master Han and I were out there.
昨夜我和韓少君徹夜未歸
Who exposed our campsite and led Meng Guo here?
到底是誰暴露營地引來孟過的
Cooked the congee?
煮粥
Bring Su Ziying here!
把蘇子嬰給我帶上來
I will punish him severely.
我要重重罰他